<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Vikram Sharma Mailthody</title>
    <link>https://msharmavikram.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Vikram Sharma Mailthody</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Vikram Sharma Mailthody</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/post/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topics for Masters (MTECH) in VLSI</title>
      <link>https://msharmavikram.github.io/post/mtech_project_ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msharmavikram.github.io/post/mtech_project_ideas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;VLSI is a very vast domain and you can put anything as research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having said that, VLSI can be classified under multiple major categories like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Front end digital design for a problem (Simulation or emulation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EDA algorithm development or improvement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backend -physical implementation or design rule optimization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;STA simplification and DFT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High performance Transistor designing and modelling- front end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fabrication - Material design and equipment design for manufacturing
Each of the above ones have large number of applications and problems which are yet to solved and lot of researchers working for the same.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better computer architecture for enhanced bus arbitration to reduce cache hit miss or better throughput, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reducing time complexity of EDA tool or development of the same for latest technology node or new material&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DRC automation to check quality and also improvise congestion in full chip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Timing optimization for DFT implementation (Lot of time is spent on checking quality of chip post fabrication)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5G or 4G LTE needs high throughput, low power, high frequency transistors which are not possible with just Silicon based ones. Compounds are added to resolve the same&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality assurance to manufacturing equipment… You can have many here!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As stated in point 5, new materials are needed to enhance performance of traditional transistors. (Also Moore’s law is reaching it tipping point… Still long way to go but research in direction to replace have been proposed - GaN is a example.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just named a examples in each categories. If you need more, please explore it in IEEE Xplore or IEEE Spectrum or VLSI Design and ReUse sites. All these provides good information on latest developments around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
